She was the girl who had everything - Money, good looks and social position. Her mother - a classic Bouvier beauty. Now they
are living amongst the souvenirs of their lives. In Grey Gardens. This is their story. A love story. Sort of.
Grey Gardens is a documentary film directed by Ellen Giffard.
Edie Bouvier Beale and her mother, Edith, two aging, eccentric relatives of Jackie
Kennedy Onassis, are the sole inhabitants of a Long Island estate.
The women reveal themselves to be misfits with outsized, engaging personalities.
Much of the conversation is centered on their pasts, as
mother and daughter now rarely leave home.
Self, played by Edith Bouvier Beale.
Self, played by Edith Ewing Bouvier Beale.
Self, played by Brooks Hyers.
Self, played by Norman Vincent Peale.
Self (uncredited), played by Jack Helmuth.
Self (uncredited), played by Albert Maysles.
Grey Gardens is a 1975 American documentary film by Albert and David Maysles.
The film depicts the everyday lives of two reclusive, upper-class women, a mother and daughter both named Edith Beale, who lived in poverty
at Grey Gardens, a derelict mansion at 3 West End Road in the wealthy Georgica Pond neighborhood of East Hampton, New York.
The film was screened at the 1976 Cannes Film Festival but
was not entered into the main competition.
Ellen Hovde and Muffie Meyer also directed, and Susan
Froemke was the associate producer.
The film was edited by Hovde, Meyer and Froemke.
In 2010, the film was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the United States National Film Registry as being "culturally, historically, or
aesthetically significant", and in the 2014 Sight and Sound poll film critics voted Grey Gardens the tenth-best documentary film of all time.
In November 2012, it topped the list of 100 greatest documentary
films of all time by PBS through public voting.
The film explores themes of cat, long island, new
york, eccentric, mansion, recluse.